# **Stephen Currie**

scurrie@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/stephen-currie/ 678-592-6932

## CIO - Technology Leader

Operations, Product Management, Strategy Development and Execution

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Extensive experience managing multiple technology functions and departments. Evolves the role of Information Technology (IT) in an organization to create digital transformation. Successfully implements Cloud and Software as a Service (SaaS) platforms. Builds balanced security processes and infrastructure to appropriately manage risk. Views IT as a business enabler. Focuses on workforce productivity to maximize output. Manages large operational teams. Track record of improving business results and employee satisfaction.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Synoptek LLC, [Irvine, CA; Denver, CO; Saint John, New Brunswick]

2016-Present

<u>Vice President of Operations / Vice President of Product Management</u>

Manages global operational team of 300 people for \$100M+/yr. IT Outsourcing company. Responsible for operational execution of IT strategy for 1,100+ mid-enterprise organizations.

Reshaped internal and external perception of operational team by improving results, effectively communicating status, and increasing employee engagement.

Implemented unified global team across multiple delivery centers in US, Canada and India with clearly defined objectives across three functional areas:

<u>Network and Security</u> – 3,100+ devices under management. Deployment, configuration, monitoring, patching and ongoing management of firewalls, routers, switches, wireless access points, and virtual private networks (VPNs).

Deployment and monitoring of anti-virus and anti-evasion software for 30,000+ end points. Managing Network Anomaly detection software, Security Incident and Event Management systems (SIEM), and performing Vulnerability Assessments for customers.

<u>Systems and Storage</u> – Managing multiple cloud (Private Cloud, AWS, Azure) and virtualization platforms (VMware and Hyper-V). Standardized backup management resulting in 80% reduction in backup failures. Implemented capacity management and storage refresh processes on 120 managed storage arrays.

<u>Application Management</u> – Managed team responsible for migrating 10,000+ mailboxes to Office365 and ongoing administration. Managing SQL and Oracle databases for multiple customers. Implementing Managed Dynamics managed service.

Significantly improved business results and operations through organizational and functional clarity:

- Improved ticket responsiveness by 70%
- Raised Service Level Agreement (SLA) met metric from 87% to 93%
- Improved Customer Satisfaction from 4.75 to 4.92 (scale of 5)
- Improved patching effectiveness of workstations and desktops
- Improved backup effectiveness from 15% SLA met to 90% SLA met
- Raised Employee Satisfaction scores by 30+ points (on a Net Promoter Score scale)
- Improved employee efficiencies by 12% (measured by revenue per employee)

#### EarthLink Business, [Atlanta, GA]

## Vice President of Product Management, IT Services

Successfully built-up \$50M+ IT services business and sold to private equity

- Managed business to industry leading growth and customer retention numbers
- Developed IT strategy and implementation plan for multiple customers with focus on Cloud services
- Key lead in the process to package, pitch and sell business

#### **Director of Product Management, IT Services**

2012-2014

Responsible for annual revenue, margin, churn and customer satisfaction targets for IT Services business

- Developed portfolio of 8 standard products to support corporate mission of becoming a leader in IT Services
  Rationalized portfolio across 5 acquired companies
  - Developed multiple Product and Marketing requirement documents
- Grew revenue organically 50% in two years by developing and executing programs around sales education, thought leadership, and new product development
- Created and executed Go-To-Market plans (white papers, webinars, product positioning)

### EarthLink, [Atlanta, GA; Los Angeles, CA]

## **Director of Product Management, Consumer Applications**

2000-2012

Responsible for annual revenue, margin, churn and customer satisfaction targets for \$15M Web Hosting business and \$10M Search and Portal business

- Increased 5 yr. EBITDA by \$4M by outsourcing 60k web sites (built business case, selected vendor, wrote migration requirements, and executed project on time and under budget)
- Proactively saved over \$200,000/yr. EBITDA by managing and renegotiating partner contracts
- Developed and executed product roadmap resulting in 20-30 releases per year across various platforms
- Maintained highest email adoption in the industry (65%) by identifying top customer demands and developing products and systems to enhance and measure progress (spamBlocker, Anonymous Email Addresses, Email Deliverability)
- Achieved \$2/user/mo. incremental revenue by creating content and advertising relationships with top-tier partners
- Managed team of up to 10 product and traffic managers

## MindSpring, [Atlanta, GA]

#### <u>Senior Development Manager, Web Applications</u>

1996-2000

Managed team of developers and UX designers to create and manage MindSpring web presence

## **INDUSTRY / AWARDS**

- Technology Services Industry Association (TSIA), 2017-Present
- Circle of Excellence award winner (Top 5% of EarthLink employees), 2011
- Technology Coalition representative for NCMEC (National Center for Missing and Exploited Children), 2009-2012
- MAAWG (Messaging Anti-Abuse Working Group), Board of Directors, 2006-2008

## **EDUCATION / SPECIALTIES**

- Bachelor of Aerospace Engineering, Georgia Tech
- Application Development, Javascript, CSS, HTML, AWS Business Professional, Operational Leadership, IT Service Management (ITSM), ITIL, Pragmatic Marketing, Media Training, Product Development Methodologies, Contract Negotiation, Cloud Hosting, Mobile, Security, Portal and Email Platforms

2014-2016